<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Thoughts, ideas and reminders | Thoughts, ideas and reminders</title><link>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/</link><description>This site contains my ideas and thoughts about anything, specially Python, Javascript, Linux, Vim... A lot of things...</description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" href="http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 02:51:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to use rsync</title><link>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-use-rsync/</link><dc:creator>Victor Hernandez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most common uses of rsync are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two folders, &lt;em&gt;folder1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;folder2&lt;/em&gt;  in different locations, i will copy the content of &lt;em&gt;folder1&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;folder2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
rsync -r folder1/* folder2&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="options"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rsync has many options that allow a lot of different actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-r&lt;/strong&gt;: This option mean recursion, this tells rsync to copy all including the files or folders that are inside other folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For recursive copy you can use the &lt;strong&gt;-a&lt;/strong&gt; option too, also this option allow preserve modification times, groups, owner and permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-v&lt;/strong&gt;: This option activate verbose for the current command, with this you can see more details of the operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-h&lt;/strong&gt;: With the -h option you can produce a more readable output when execute a rsync command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-use-rsync/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 17:37:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to setup a virtualenv with python3</title><link>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-setup-a-virtualenv-with-python3/</link><dc:creator>Victor Hernandez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a topic that use to confuse me, so here i share a very good solution for this. I work with this steps in Debian 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First at all, be sure that you have installed Python3 on your system, if not, install it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
apt-get install python3.4&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then install pip if you don't have installed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wget &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bootstrap.pypa.io/get-pip.py"&gt;https://bootstrap.pypa.io/get-pip.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python3 get-pip.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, install virtualenv and create the environment with python3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pip3 install virtualenv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Create the virtualenv environment without packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;virtualenv projectname --no-site-packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cd projectname&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source bin/activate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can try typing &lt;strong&gt;python3&lt;/strong&gt;. For deactivate the virtualenv:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
deactivate&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>python3</category><category>virtualenv</category><guid>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-setup-a-virtualenv-with-python3/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 16:42:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why i began with this?... Never forget.</title><link>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/why-i-began-with-this-never-forget/</link><dc:creator>Victor Hernandez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a long time i wanted to start a blog by multiple reasons, like for example put the things that i learn every day, whether they are or not technology, but especially technology. Also to write about procedures, tutorials for me (And that maybe can be useful to someone else), questions that i had, i searched, i answered, but with the time i forget and i had to search again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want also through the creation of content for this site, to get better my english language skills (German language in a future too), and also, even is my native language, of spanish too. At this moment i am not an expert in nothing, i've seen themes by here and by there, so you could say that this is not the most reliable site to apply concepts, but the idea is to show my learning path and if this can be helpful to somebody, well, welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go by the path of development, in fact, i've been studying Python/Js about three years ago at a rate overwhelmingly slow, that un retrospective shows me all the time that i lost, and even so, how much i've learned. For several months until the day that this post was writen, i accelerated the speed of my self-study and i've learned a lot of things more deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, i will write the topics that until now i know or that i want to learn in a very-close future, and i will put a measurement scale  about my current knowledge in these. Also these will be the topics that i want to polish, so possibly in a future i will review this post and make a comparison of my progress. The categories for the measurement will be: 1 for "Without experience, but i want to learn", 2 for "Prior experience but rusty", 3 for "Proficient".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux - 3 (A lot to learn yet but very comfortable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Html - 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vim.org/"&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; - 3 (I've learned thanks to one of the smartets persons in the field)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git - 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javascript - 3 (I've learned in previous works, tutorials and very specially in Freecodecamp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; - 2 (My favorite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Css - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.freedesktop.org/software/systemd/man/systemd-nspawn.html"&gt;Systemd-nspawn&lt;/a&gt; - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL -2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aerospike - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RethinkDB - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows Server - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>javascript</category><category>linux</category><category>python</category><category>technology</category><category>thoughts</category><category>vim</category><guid>http://theviajerock.github.io/blog/posts/why-i-began-with-this-never-forget/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:06:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>